It's... raining.
It's raining.
But, but!
It doesn't matter. Kobato is ready!
I am going to collect more kompeito!
That was close!
Do... Ba... To...
Now I'm all covered in mud, thanks to you!
Kobato.
What should I do?
Even the most obvious of things
Are always such a challenge
I want to laugh when I'm happy
And sing whenever I want
Is all
They say my dreams will come true someday
But when will "someday" come?
I can't wait forever
On "1, 2, 3!" I'll spread open my arms
And let the light gather around me
Where is it?
Please tell me what I can do
I make the most of getting hurt
And run with all my might
Despite how many dozens of times I fall
And start crying
I surprise myself
In how much I believe in tomorrow
...A Gift from the Rain.
D-Don't worry about getting muddy, Ioryogi-san.
The rain will wash the mud off.
What do you mean, don't worry?!
Then I'll be soaking wet!
Kobato?
Good morning.
Ms. Sayaka?
Um... Ms. Sayaka?
What is it?
Where are you going?
I'm going to your home, Kobato.
Huh?
Here we are.
Wow!
But, but... it is all right for me to live here?
Sure, as long as you don't mind.
Come along, let's go inside.
Yes ma'am!
Let me introduce you.
This is my friend Chitose.
She manages this apartment building.
H-How do you do?! My name is Kobato Hanato.
Kobato, is it? It's nice to meet you.
I'm Chitose Mihara.
Don't hesitate to ask me if you
have any questions at all.
Yes ma'am!
Thank you Chitose, for all your help.
Well then Kobato, I must be getting
back to the kindergarten.
Oh, yes! Thank you very much.
I'll be over later to help.
There you go again.
Always worried about others.
Kobato?
Yes?
Welcome aboard.
She seems like such a nice person!
This is where you say, " Thank you for having
me, I hope I'm not too much trouble."
Uh, thank you for having me.
My name is Kobato Hanato.
I hope you're not too much trouble.
No, you're not the one being troubled.
What time do you think your
things will be arriving?
Huh?! Um, uh, well!
This is it!
But where's your bedding and such?
I don't have any!
Oh?
Well then come along, let me show you around.
Okay!
This is a beautiful building.
Do you think so? Thank you.
Oh, wow!
What a nice room, don't you
think so Ioryogi-san?
Ioryogi-san?
Huh? Huh?
Where could he have disappeared to?
Dobato...
How could you dare leave me behind?!
How many times do I have to tell you?!
I am a stuffed toy here!
Sorry!
Just give me a break!
Hey!
Y-Yes, yes.
Kindergarten's about to start.
That's right!
We'd better hurry!
We're going to be late!
I'm sorry. Are you okay?
I'm fine. I'm more worried about him.
I'm so sorry. You're all covered in mud.
He's kind of cute!
Good! He's all cleaned up now.
Here. See ya!
Thank you very much!
She knows how to be considerate, unlike you.
Kobato.
How did you like your room?
Great! There was a roof and I could lie around
on the floor, and it was wonderful!
That's good. I'm glad to hear it.
Kobato!
Let's play!
I'm cleaning right now.
Then I'll help!
Me too!
Thank you very much!
What do you want me to do?
Let me see.
Hey, what about me?
You didn't have to go so far as
to get her an apartment.
Why, everyone seems to be so
happy since she arrived.
Don't you go bullying her now.
You're just going to...
You're just going to get yourself hurt again.
Maybe you're right.
Right now you need to be wary of everyone.
Isn't it nice that the rain has let up?
There's no kindergarten tomorrow, so I'm
going to collect a lot of kompeito, Ioryogi-san!
Yeah!
But it was sunny until just
a few minutes ago.
This is why I told you to bring an umbrella.
I'm sorry.
It doesn't look like it's going
to stop any time soon.
I guess you'll just have to get wet.
Hey! That's not fair, you staying dry!
You don't have an umbrella?
No...
Well then, here.
Please use it if you like.
But...
You can have it. I had it for customers, anyway.
Um... I'll come and return
it when it stops raining!
Okay. I'll be waiting for you.
Yes! Thank you very much!
That was a pretty normal
encounter, for you, Kobato.
So you're going to keep this up?
Yes!
I'm going to gather information on people
who need their hearts mended here!
I guess you could be right in a way.
Looks like a lot of people use this place.
Kobato is ready!
I couldn't find any information.
What's up?
The umbrella I borrowed is gone!
What?!
Someone must have taken it by mistake.
They probably just took it.
What? Is it okay just to take
someone's umbrella?
Of course not!
Oh, no...
That umbrella was lent to me by
the person at the cake shop.
Hey.
We meet again!
Oh... yesterday...
What's the matter?
My umbrella's gone.
Oh?
Here!
What?
This is mine. I'll lend it to you.
But...
No worries.
My house is really close, anyway.
Besides, if you don't have an
umbrella, you'll get him wet.
Right?
Hey Mutsumi!
Be careful of that junk food.
You'll get fat again.
Shut up Katsuragi, you fool!
Wait a minute!
Um!
Thank you very much!
You wait for me or I'm going to hit you!
You'd hit me even if I did wait!
Say that again?!
Hey! Katsuragi!
There are those who will lend you their umbrella
even if it means getting wet themselves.
Good morning!
Good morning, Kobato.
You've got floor markings on your cheek.
Huh?
S-See you later!
How embarrassing!
Floor markings on my cheek?!
Chitose must have thought I was weird!
Good morning!
Huh?
Thank you for the use of your umbrella.
I'm surprised you found my school.
Yes, well I went back to the cake shop to
apologize for having lost his umbrella
and he told me that the green sailor
suits were this school's uniform.
Ioryogi-san is grateful, too.
Ioryogi?
Yes.
Oh, this doll? Wow, that's an unusual name.
My name is Kobato Hanato.
I'm Mutsumi Tadokoro.
Mutsumi!
Your hair's crooked in the back.
Huh? Be quiet! Keep it to yourself!
Oh no. Where, where?
I don't see anything wrong.
I have floor markings on my cheek.
That really doesn't make me feel any better.
S-Sorry.
Don't worry about it.
I got to go. I have morning practice.
That boy though, he's not very kind, is he?
He's almost like Fujimoto.
Oh no! If I'm late, he'll be mean again!
You are one minute and
twenty-three seconds late.
O-One minute?
Late is late whether it's one minute or not.
I-I'm sorry.
You were sleeping until the
last minute, weren't you?
No. The floor mark is already gone.
Don't tell me you fell out of your bedding.
I don't have any bedding!
Huh?
Good morning, Kobato.
Oh. Good morning.
Has Fujimoto been giving you a hard time?
Well, um...
He's a bit rough around the edges,
but you know he's a good kid.
Let me know if he hassles you, though.
I'll give him the fist punishment!
F-Fist?
Yes. Like good old days.
Old days?
Hey, it's finally a nice day.
We're airing out the bedding for nap time.
Oh! Yes! I'm on my way!
Goodbye, Kobato!
Yes, goodbye!
Looks like rain again.
Kobato, do you have an umbrella?
No, I don't.
Fujimoto, you do, don't you?
Why don't you two go home together?
I'm busy after this.
Kobato, take my umbrella.
I wouldn't be caught dead sharing
an umbrella with you, anyway.
Sharing an umbrella?
Couples share one umbrella.
Just like Ms. Sayaka said.
It really started raining.
Hey!
The person who took it by accident
must have brought it back.
Hey, Kobato?
We meet again.
Oh, Mutsumi Tadokoro!
Just call me Mutsumi. What are you up to?
The umbrella was returned!
Huh? Why, that's great!
Yes! Are you shopping again, Mutsumi?
Yeah. Kendo practice is really tough.
I'm always starving afterwards.
You really put yourself into it.
Oh, but uh...
I can't eat too much or I'll get fat.
Here. Why don't you take this?
Are you sure?
I'm sure. Here. See ya!
That's a couple sharing an umbrella, isn't it?
Mutsumi!
Mutsumi...
She was so sad.
What can I do to make her feel better?
I don't know. This one's a bit delicate.
Good evening. Will you open the door, please?
Yes?
Oh my! Are you alright?
Yes.
Sorry to bother you.
How do you do, I'm Chiho, the
apartment manager's daughter.
I'm Chise.
Oh, hello. My name is Kobato Hanato.
We heard you didn't have any bedding.
Uh, no.
Our mother said to use this, if you like.
Are you serious?!
It's used, but if you don't mind.
See you later!
Thank you so very much!
They gave me a futon!
What good does it do you if you're
the one getting the healing?
Oh, that's right.
I'm going to get Mutsumi to feel better again.
How do you plan to do that?
Well... I'm just going to do my best!
Hey. What are you planning to do?
I think it's best you leave her alone for now.
Excuse me!
M-May I have a word with you?
It's about Mutsumi!
Please?!
Ah, what do you mean?
Like I said, I want you to share an
umbrella with Mutsumi, too.
Please!
What do you mean "Mutsumi, too," idiot.
Is it not possible?
Mutsumi!
What's this all about?
The other day... Well you had a
very sad expression, so...
That time when you were sharing
an umbrella with another girl.
I wasn't necessarily...
Then why that expression?
Well that was because...
That was because...
Excuse me if I've stuck my
foot in something here,
but I just wanted Mutsumi to
feel better and smile again.
So!
Here! Please share this umbrella with Mutsumi!
Huh?
Kobato?
I'm asking you.
You'd be disappointing that other
girl, now wouldn't you?
Get in.
Wha... What's this? You don't have to do this!
She's not my girlfriend or anything.
Huh?
That was just... well you see she said she forgot
her umbrella so I just walked her home.
That's all.
Mutsumi. Come on.
What are you waiting for? Let's go!
Uh!
Katsuragi!
Wait for me! Can't you see I'm getting wet?!
Don't walk so close to me.
Quit complaining.
There's not enough room in here!
You're impossible.
But it's true.
What do you expect me to do about it?
It's a small umbrella.
Mutsumi doesn't look particularly happy.
She's fine, she's fine.
Is that right?
This is strange, Ioryogi.
What's strange?
There's another kompeito.
Isn't that why you mended her heart?
I-I just wanted her to be happy
and helped out a bit.
Oh well, whatever. Her heart was healed,
and that's what counts.
Is that right?
The increased kompeito is hard proof.
Well that's good, then.
I wonder if we're ever going to get through this.
What was that I just sensed?
What is it, Kohaku?
Oh, it's nothing, Shuichiro.
Let's go.
It went pretty well this time.
I guess I can give you a fairly high score.
Are you serious?!
Oh! Are you okay, Ioryogi-san?!
Do... Ba... To...
You get a ZERO!
What?!
You're mean, Ioryogi-san!
You just said you'd give me a good score!
It's all because of you that I'm
continually covered in mud and soot!
It's okay. It will wash off in the rain!
Nothing will wash off my anger!
Oh, come on!
Everyone dreams of flying
But they let gravity trick them
Honestly, everyone is already able to fly
I bet the reason that child looks so terribly sad
Is because he
Accidentally lost his shadow somewhere
In that case
If I could just tell you, "Thank you,"
And you laugh and reply, "Thank you"
That exchange would fill you with joy
It would make you feel so happy
There's nothing to worry about
Since we're together
It's strange how I'm crying
Even though I'm happy
Next episode
...Spring Green and the Flutter of the Heart.
Even though I'm happy
Next episode
...Spring Green and the Flutter of the Heart.